In order to choose an appropriate plot for your data,
为了给数据选择合适的图表类型
you need to understand the types of the data you have.
你需要理解数据的数据类型
One common method divide data into four data types: Nominal,
常用的分类方法将数据分为四大类：定类 (无序分类)、
ordinal, interval and ratio.
定序 (有序分类)、定距以及定比
The first two are known as qualitative or categorical types while
前两个通常也被归为定性或分类数据
the last two are known as quantitative or numeric types.
后两个则被归为定量或数值数据
Furthermore, quantitative types include a second kind of
除此之外 数值数据类型还有
classification: Discrete or continuous.
另一种分类方法：     连续型或离散型
Features that are categorical are those that act as non-numeric labels on the data.
分类数据的特征表现为非数值的文本标记
Nominal data are pure labels without any natural ordering.
定类 (无序分类) 数据是没有任何自然排序的纯文本标记
Examples of this include things like,
这一类数据的示例包括：
movie genre or country.
电影类型或者国家
Ordinal variables are also labels but unlike
定序 (有序分类) 数据本质是也是文本标签 但是跟定类数据不同的是
nominal variables these include an intrinsic ordering.
不同类别之间是可以排序的
Examples of this type of variable include,
这一类数据的示例包括：
letter grade on a test or ranking at the end of a competition.
表示考试成绩的字母或者比赛排名
While categorical variables might be recorded numerically,
虽然分类变量可能用数字来表示
we should not make the mistake of performing numeric operations with them.
你却不能对它们进行数值运算
For example, let's say that the rankings
比如 年度最佳书籍评比
above come from a list of the best books of the year.
得到的数字排名
We wouldn't expect the goodness of the first and second place books combined to
我们不可能说将第一名和第二名的书籍评比结果相加
equal that of the third place book or
然后等于第三名书籍的评比结果
that the second and third place books some of to the first place book.
或者说将第三名的减去第二名的得到第一名的结果
You can only say that first place is better than second place,
你只能说第一名的书比第二名的书更好
and second place is better than third,
第二名的比第三名的好
but not by how much.
但并不能衡量到底好多少
Knowing the difference between first second doesn't necessarily
第一名和第二名的差距并不等于
tell you that the difference between second third will be the same.
第二名和第三名之间的差距
Quantitative data on the other hand,
数值型的数据则恰恰相反
take numerical values that allow for mathematical operations.
它们是可以进行数学运算的
For interval type data,
比如对于定距数据来说
differences between numeric values are meaningful.
数据之间的数值差距是有意义的
Examples of this type of variable include,
这种类型的变量包括
year or temperature in Celsius.
年 还有摄氏温度
An increase or decrease of one point will
数据上增加或者减少一个单位都具备同一个含义
mean the same thing no matter what you have at each scale.
无论数据的规模如何
Ratio type data also allows for difference comparisons,
定比数据之间也可以进行大小的比较
but also requires an additional property.
但是它们还需要满足另一个特性
For a variable to be considered ratio type,
对于定比数据而言
there must be a meaningful zero point such that ratio judgments are meaningful.
必须存在一个有意义的零点 使得比值之间的判断是有意义的
Consider the earlier example regarding temperature in Celsius.
回到之前的提到的温度的例子
Since temperature is interval,
因为温度是定距的
the difference between five degrees and 10 degrees
所以 5 摄氏度和 10 摄氏度之间的差距和
is the same as that between 10 and 15 degrees.
10 摄氏度和 15 摄氏度之间的差距是一样的
But Celsius is not a ratio type variable.
但是摄氏度并不属于定比这个类别
You wouldn't say that 10 degrees is twice as hot as
因为你不会说 10 度比 5 度要热两倍
five degrees or 15 degrees three times as hot as five.
或者说 15 度比 5 度要热三倍
Examples of ratio type data include: the length of a document by word count,
定比数据的例子包括文档的字数
or measurement of mass in kilograms.
或者以千克为单位的物体重量
All quantitative variables, whether interval or ratio
所有数值变量 不管是定距还是定比
type can also be classified as discrete or continuous.
都可以被划分为离散和连续两种类型
Discrete quantitative variables can only take on specific values,
离散型变量只能取特定的数值
while continuous variables can take on any value.
而连续型变量则能取任意的数值
Year and word count are examples of discrete variables.
年和字数属于离散型变量
They can only take on integer values.
它们只能取整数值
Temperature and mass are examples of continuous variables.
温度和重量则是连续型变量的例子
These variables can take on any number of decimal values,
这些值可以有任意的小数点位数
if we had instruments capable of recording them with that precision.
只要我们具备测得相应精度的仪器
Cut.
Cut.